# Chris Colatos, MSc, ACT, FAHE

ccolatos@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/colatoschris



San Francisco Bay Area/Remote





### SUMMARY

Education & Academic Thought Leader

Three decades transforming vision into action as an impactful organizational and education leader and strategist. Inclusive learning innovator with diverse teams and audiences. Building high-performing teams and fostering inclusive work cultures, specializing in human-centered learning experiences that catalyze system-wide change. Vision to transform how organizations engage their audiences and each other. Excelling in leadership positions overseeing colleges, EdTech, active and experiential learning design teams, Learning and Development departments, and academic programs.



## EXPERIENCE

# Chief Learning Officer (2017 – Present) **Unforgettable Learning**

- · Champion leadership and program development through data-informed, focused teaching and learning experiences, strategies, curricula, assessments, analytics, and technology.
- · Own the overall design, development, and execution of learning and development initiatives for staff employees.
- · Manage end-to-end program operations, including budget, communications, program delivery, and evaluation.
- Develop and maintain learning solutions that satisfy the needs of a diverse set of learners (instructor-led videos, online courses, quick reference guides, job aids, and performance support).
- Work closely with subject matter experts (SMEs), external vendors, and colleagues to create and evaluate innovative and effective learning solutions.
- · Develop design documents, storyboards, scripts, media lists, and assessment tools.
- Translate content into visual descriptions (graphics, animations, interactive charts and graphs, video-based scenarios).
- · Drive effective project management in all projects by identifying scope, key stakeholders, and RACI.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Perform learning-needs analysis and prescribe appropriate learning experiences to close performance gaps.
- Enable career path development by identifying relevant competencies, helping employees set career goals, and managing career expectations.

#### Director of Learning Design, North America (2020 – 2022) Chair of Curriculum Design, North America (2015 – 2019) SAE Institute, North America

- $\cdot\,\,$  Founded the Learning Design department for the North America system of 7 colleges.
- Led learning designers and learning media developers to develop and implement creative arts higher education teaching and active learning applications.
- · Served as the institutional specialist for online and hybrid learning.
- · Led academic and instructional innovation initiatives with emerging technology.
- $\cdot\,$  Integrated learning design in the curriculum development of new academic programs and the enhancement of legacy programs.
- $\cdot$  Leveraged new LMS and learning platforms to optimize student engagement.
- · Acted as a culture champion by creating opportunities for growth and communication.



## HIGHLIGHTS

Owned the vision and development of a new Learning Design department serving 7 colleges; created 400+ learning experiences in the first 6 months while establishing the department from the ground up.

Founded a grassroots communityfocused organization, which regularly trained 40 Pixar artists and thousands of technologists, artists, and professionals.

Volunteer Instructional Designer at After-School All-Stars; developed robust arts programs in underserved communities.



# MASTER OF SCIENCE, DIGITAL EDUCATION (Hons) The University of Edinburgh

**BACHELOR OF APPLIED SCIENCE, SOUND ARTS** (Hons) Ex'pression Center for New Media

CERTIFICATE, COMPUTATIONAL THINKING FOR PROBLEM-SOLVING University of Pennsylvania

LEARNING ANALYTICS: PROCESS AND THEORY

Columbia University

INTELLIGENT AUDIO SYSTEMS
Stanford University

**CREATIVE CODING** 

Gray Area Foundation for the Arts

CERTIFICATE, ALGORITHMIC COMPUTER MUSIC (WACM)

University of California, Santa Cruz

APPLE CERTIFIED MASTER TRAINER
Apple ACT T3 (28 Certifications)



## SKILLS

Communication
Public Speaking
Online/eLearning
Creative Direction
People Leadership
Strategic Planning
Teaching & Training
Instructional Design
Project Management
Program Development
Organizational Strategy
Leadership Development
Curriculum Development
Student Success & Coaching





San Francisco Bay Area/Remote





## **EXPERIENCE**

Education & Academic Thought Leader

Director of Education (2018 - 2021) Academic Programs Chair (2010 – 2018) Executive Director, Professional Training (2008 – 2014) Program Development Manager (2009 – 2012) Academic Course Director / Assistant Professor (2002 – 2010)

#### **Expression College**

· Owned the vision and performance for all academic and student affairs within the

Chris Colatos, MSc, ACT, FAHE

- · Hired and mentored 70+ Program Chairs, administrators, and faculty supporting thousands of students.
- · Represented the college and built internal and external federal, state, and local regulatory, accreditation, and community partnerships.
- · Created a multi-year strategy to design and implement student-centered active education programs and increase student success from matriculation to graduation and into careers.
- · Developed structures for regular data reflection on organizational and student progress and identifying opportunities for action.
- · Collaborated cross-functionally to highlight innovation and drive change management across the organization.

#### Chief Creative (1993 - Present)

#### THE STUDI/O

- · Lead the organizational strategy, vision, and creative direction.
- · Serve as the principal consultant and primary liaison to support the goals of hundreds of artists and organizations.
- · Drive the planning, project management, and delivery of solutions spanning music and sound, games, interactive media, AR/VR, mixed media composition, design, performance, and installation.
- · Partner and produce for high-profile brands, including Apple, Google, LeapFrog, Honor Code, Legends The Game, Robot Invader, Eagre Games, OtoCast, Ableton, Universal Audio, Tarpan Studios, Twisted Tools, iZotope, PETA, Stardust Brands, Harbor Picture Company, GQ, Salvatore Ferragamo, and Vogue.
- · Deliver top-quality music and audio production for globally recognized artists, including Greg Phillinganes, Siedah Garrett, Narada Michael Walden, James Taylor, Carole King, Smokey Robinson, Billy Joel, Sting, Elton John, and Katy Perry.

#### Lecturer & Instructional Designer (2012 – 2015)

#### San Francisco State University

- · Lecturer and Instructional Designer for Graduate and Undergraduate level courses, including Sound Design, Advanced Recording & Production, Post Production, Electronic Music, and Game Audio.
- · Received a student review average of 9.73/10.
- · Established and administered the SFSU CEL certification programs.



## **TECHNICAL**

Articulate Storyline 360, Adobe Captivate, Canvas, Learning Management Systems (LMS), Instructional Technology, SCORM, ADDIE, SAM, Kirkpatrick, Google Suite, Microsoft Office, Apple Suite, Camtasia, Adobe Creative Cloud, Creative Technology

Acoustical Society of America



#### **ASSOCIATIONS**

Advance HE Association for Computing Machinery Audio Engineering Society Center for New Music Fractured Atlas Game Audio Network Guild Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Interactive Audio Special Interest Group Intl Society for Music Information Retrieval Society for Electro-Acoustic Music in the US Society of Professional Audio Recording Services Special Interest Group on Computer Graphics



### LEADERSHIP

Augmenting the Reality of Interactive Learning Environments (2023)

Learning Efficacy of Multimedia in Interactive Augmented Reality Environments (2017)

Effects of Arts Education and Underserved Communities (2016)

Adaptive Learning Design Implications: Effects of Multimedia on Learning Efficacy and Cognitive Load (2016)

Fellow, Advance HE (2016)



## EARLY CAREER

**Executive Director** Apple Training Hawaii (2011 – 2015)

Producer, Composer, Music Supervisor Country Road Films (2011 – 2015)

Producer, Songwriter, Arranger, Engineer Narada Michael Walden, Tarpan Studios (2001 -2004)